Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have a very special lesson for everyone.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节非常特别的课程。
It's a new level for us.
这对我们来说是一个新的级别。
Right.
没错。
It's an advanced media lesson and we are going to be listening to an apology.
这是一节高级媒体课，我们将要听一段道歉。
Well, it's an apology letter but we're going to actually have someone talk it out.
嗯，这是一封道歉信，但我们会让某人把它读出来。
Right.
对。
So, what's happening here is someone is reading a letter they've written and they're trying
所以，这里的情况是有人在读他们写的一封信，他们试图
to apologize for something and we don't really know what this something is but I want everyone
为某事道歉，我们不太清楚这件事是什么，但我希望大家
to really listen here to the words that are being used and to the ways in which we can
仔细听这里使用的词语以及我们
say sorry because as they say, there are a thousand ways to say I'm sorry.
说对不起的方式，因为俗话说，说对不起有一千种方式。
Dear Mary, I come here today this way because I need to apologize to you.
亲爱的Mary，我今天以这种方式来到这里，是因为我需要向你道歉。
I failed you.
我辜负了你。
Although I did not lie to you in words, I lied to you with faces that did not belong
虽然我没有用言语欺骗你，但我用不属于我的
to me.
面孔欺骗了你。
I never meant to ruin the friendship that meant the world to me.
我从没想过要毁掉对我意义重大的友谊。
You mean the world to me and now I come to you asking for forgiveness.
你对我意味着全世界，现在我来到你面前请求原谅。
If in your heart you find you can't, then I will understand and learn from this experience.
如果你心里觉得无法原谅，那么我会理解，并从这次经历中学习。
You came into my life at a time when I needed you the most.
你在我最需要你的时候走进了我的生活。
We talked about so many things that I started to realize my heart and my soul could actually
我们谈论了那么多事情，以至于我开始意识到我的心和灵魂其实可以
feel something other than hurt.
感受到除了伤害之外的东西。
You placed comfort where there was fear, confidence when there was doubt, a shoulder where tears
你在恐惧的地方带来了安慰，在怀疑的地方带来了信心，在泪水
could fall and completeness where there was emptiness.
可以落下的地方提供了肩膀，在空虚的地方带来了完整。
I wanted to hold on to this so badly that I did whatever it took for you to notice.
我太想抓住这一切了，以至于我做了任何事来引起你的注意。
What I didn't realize was that I could lose my entire being, all of who I was and all
我没有意识到的是，我可能会失去我的整个存在，我的一切以及
of that I had placed in you.
我放在你身上的一切。
I wanted to be the one who would be there when you needed to talk.
我想成为那个在你需要倾诉时陪伴你的人。
I wanted to be the comfort for your soul when the world was too much to handle.
我想成为你灵魂的慰藉，当世界难以承受时。
I wanted to be strong for you when everything else seemed impossible.
我想在你面前坚强，当其他一切似乎都不可能时。
I wanted to love you in only the way you deserve to be loved, never realizing that I was destroying
我想以你应得的方式爱你，却从未意识到我正在摧毁
myself and you.
我自己和你。
Somehow I needed you to be a part of my life.
不知怎的，我需要你成为我生活的一部分。
The only problem was that I was willing to jeopardize everything to get that done.
唯一的问题是，我愿意为了达到这个目的而危及一切。
All the things that I told you about how I felt and how you make me feel were true.
我告诉你的关于我的感受以及你给我的感觉，所有这些都是真的。
Everything else mattered to me except hearing the laughter in your voice when you were happy.
除了听到你快乐时笑声中的喜悦，其他一切对我来说都重要。
You made my days easy to get through and my nights peaceful.
你让我的日子容易度过，让我的夜晚平静安宁。
You helped me look forward to another day.
你帮助我期待新的一天。
Even though distance separated us, just being was enough.
即使距离将我们分开，仅仅存在就足够了。
I'm sorry for hurting you and if I had to do it all over again, I would have been 100%
我很抱歉伤害了你，如果我能重来一次，我会百分之百地
with you.
和你在一起。
Forgive me please.
请原谅我。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So the guy seemed to be pretty sad.
所以那个家伙看起来挺伤心的。
Yeah, this is a very intense.
是的，这非常强烈。
Well, it's not a dialogue.
嗯，这不是对话。
It's a monologue.
这是独白。
One person is reading it.
一个人在朗读它。
So it's a very intense monologue.
所以这是一个非常强烈的独白。
Very romantic.
非常浪漫。
Yeah, romantic, but also an air of melancholy.
是的，浪漫，但也带着一丝忧郁。
Yeah, that's true.
是的，没错。
He's kind of like apologizing and at the same time expressing love and all these feelings.
他有点像在道歉，同时又在表达爱意和所有这些情感。
So it was very interesting.
所以非常有趣。
But why don't we take a look at a couple of phrases.
但我们为什么不看看几个短语呢。
Now in advanced media, we're not going to analyze the entire dialogue or as we do in
在高级媒体课中，我们不会像在其他级别那样分析整个对话，
the other levels, actually pick out items for language takeaway or fluency builder.
或者挑选出语言要点或流利度构建的条目。
So in advanced media, we're only going to pick out a couple of words and phrases and
所以在高级媒体课中，我们只会挑选几个单词和短语，
just talk about it and talk about the topic in general.
然后讨论它们，并总体上讨论这个话题。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So one of the first phrases that we decided to talk about here is this phrase, I failed
所以我们决定讨论的第一个短语是“I failed you”，
you because this is really the theme of the letter.
因为这真的是这封信的主题。
Right.
对。
So if you fail someone, it means that you let that person down.
所以如果你辜负了某人，意思是你让那个人失望了。
Okay, so you fail someone, I failed you, or you can say, he failed me.
好的，所以你辜负了某人，我辜负了你，或者你可以说，他辜负了我。
So when I really needed that person the most, that person didn't come through or let me
所以当我最需要那个人的时候，那个人没有做到或让我
down or failed me.
失望或辜负了我。
All right, so let's give an example maybe.
好的，那我们举个例子吧。
I needed my brother to pick me up because I don't have a car.
我需要我哥哥来接我，因为我没有车。
And my brother was supposed to pick me up at four o'clock and he forgot.
我哥哥应该在四点钟来接我，但他忘了。
He didn't come.
他没来。
He really failed me.
他真的辜负了我。
All right, he failed you.
好的，他辜负了你。
Yeah, I was disappointed.
是的，我很失望。
Well, this isn't that's not as serious as what happened here in this letter, I think.
嗯，这没有这封信里发生的事情那么严重，我想。
Right?
对吧？
I think so.
我想是的。
But we could talk about what did happen.
但我们可以讨论到底发生了什么。
I think I have a theory.
我想我有一个猜测。
And I know you have a theory.
我知道你有一个猜测。
So we can talk about that in a minute.
所以我们一会儿可以讨论这个。
But before that, we have some other phrases about forgiveness and disappointment.
但在此之前，我们还有一些关于原谅和失望的短语。
Right.
对。
So he also said, you mean the world to me and now I come to you asking for forgiveness.
所以他还说：“你对我意味着全世界，现在我来到你面前请求原谅。”
Okay, so we've got a positive and a negative.
好的，所以我们有积极和消极的一面。
So the positive here is you mean the world to me.
所以积极的一面是“你对我意味着全世界”。
You mean the world to me.
你对我意味着全世界。
This means you are so important to me.
这意味着你对我非常重要。
You're one of the most important people in my life.
你是我生命中最重要的一个人。
You're worth the entire world, in my opinion.
在我看来，你值得整个世界。
Yeah, it's a very poetic way of saying you're very important.
是的，这是一种非常诗意的说法，表示你非常重要。
And then he says, and now I come asking for your forgiveness.
然后他说：“现在我来到你面前请求你的原谅。”
Okay.
好的。
So this implies that he did something wrong.
所以这暗示他做错了什么。
I come asking for forgiveness.
我来请求原谅。
So in English, we ask for forgiveness.
所以在英语中，我们请求原谅。
You can also beg for forgiveness.
你也可以乞求原谅。
So please, please forgive me.
所以请，请原谅我。
But you can't demand forgiveness.
但你不能要求原谅。
I demand you forgive.
我要求你原谅。
No, that doesn't quite work.
不，那不太行得通。
All right.
好的。
What else do we have?
我们还有什么？
We've got the world again here.
这里又出现了“世界”这个词。
He says he, the guy who's reading, he says, you know, I wanted to be the comfort for your
他说，那个朗读的家伙说，你知道，我想成为你灵魂的
soul.
慰藉。
So this is very, again, poetic, when the world was too much to handle.
所以这又是非常诗意的，当世界难以承受时。
Too much to handle is a really important English phrase.
“Too much to handle”是一个非常重要的英语短语。
And I'm sure you've heard it before, but we could talk about a little bit here.
我相信你以前听过，但我们可以在这里稍微讨论一下。
Right.
对。
So he says when everything else was too much to handle.
所以他说当其他一切都难以承受时。
So everything was so difficult or it was overwhelming.
所以一切都非常困难或让人不知所措。
Right.
对。
So you could say even in the office, man, all this work I have to do, it's too much
所以即使在办公室，你也可以说，天啊，所有这些工作我必须做，真是
to handle.
难以承受。
Right, right.
对，对。
Okay.
好的。
Too much to handle.
难以承受。
You could also say a child is too much to handle.
你也可以说一个孩子难以应付。
I think they said this about my brother.
我想他们是这样说我哥哥的。
He was very difficult growing up.
他小时候很难相处。
Too hard.
太难了。
He's too, he's too difficult to handle.
他太难，太难应付了。
All right.
好吧。
Well, what about in the part where he says you place comfort where there was fear, confidence
嗯，那部分他说“你在恐惧的地方带来了安慰，在怀疑的地方带来了自信”呢？
where there was doubt.
在怀疑的地方。
So this structure is interesting because you placed something where there used to be something
所以这个结构很有趣，因为你把某样东西放在了原本有另一样东西的地方。
else.
别的东西。
So you're replacing something, you're changing something for something else.
所以你是在替换某样东西，把一样东西换成另一样。
It's an exchange.
这是一种交换。
So you could say you placed comfort where there was fear, you placed happiness, where
所以你可以说你在恐惧的地方带来了安慰，你在悲伤的地方带来了快乐。
there was sadness.
在悲伤的地方。
Where there was sadness.
So it's always like kind of opposites, right?
所以这总是有点像反义词，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Light where there was dark.
在黑暗的地方带来了光明。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So that's an interesting format of saying something.
所以这是一种有趣的表达方式。
You did something where there used to be something else.
你在原本有另一样东西的地方做了某件事。
All right.
好吧。
And what about this word to jeopardize?
那“jeopardize”这个词呢？
All right.
好吧。
This is a good one.
这是个好词。
I always think of the TV game show Jeopardy, but that's a noun.
我总想到电视游戏节目《Jeopardy》，但那是名词。
This here is a verb to jeopardize and that means to put something in danger or to risk
这里是动词“jeopardize”，意思是把某物置于危险中或冒失去某物的风险。
losing something.
失去某物。
Okay.
好的。
So to jeopardize your health if you're doing something dangerous.
所以如果你做危险的事，就是危及你的健康。
So smoking jeopardizes one's health.
所以吸烟危及健康。
You're putting your health at risk.
你在拿健康冒险。
Or I don't want to jeopardize my savings by investing everything I have in stocks.
或者我不想把所有积蓄都投资股票来危及我的存款。
That means I would prefer to do something safer.
那意味着我宁愿做更安全的事。
So you don't like to jeopardize your well-being.
所以你不喜欢危及你的幸福。
I like to play it safe, as we say.
我喜欢稳妥行事，就像我们常说的。
All right.
好吧。
Very good.
非常好。
And last but not least, this almost the last phrase when he says, even though distance
最后但同样重要的是，这几乎是最后一句，当他说“即使距离把我们分开，仅仅存在就足够了”。
separated us, just being was enough.
仅仅存在就足够了。
What does he mean when he says just being was enough?
他说的“仅仅存在就足够了”是什么意思？
All right.
好吧。
This is very romantic, intensely romantic.
这非常浪漫，极其浪漫。
He says, even though we were far apart, just being, so just existing, just breathing was
他说，即使我们相隔很远，仅仅存在，所以仅仅活着，仅仅呼吸就足够了。
enough.
足够了。
So just knowing that she's in the world was enough for him to feel happy.
所以仅仅知道她在这个世界上就足以让他感到快乐。
So that's what he means with just being was enough.
这就是他说的“仅仅存在就足够了”的意思。
Right.
对。
So just being is existing.
所以“仅仅存在”就是活着。
It's being alive.
就是活着。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
I think we should listen to this apology letter one more time and we'll be back.
我觉得我们应该再听一遍这封道歉信，然后回来。
Dear Mary, I come here today this way because I need to apologize to you.
亲爱的玛丽，我今天这样来见你，是因为我需要向你道歉。
I failed you.
我辜负了你。
Although I did not lie to you in words, I lied to you with faces that did not belong
虽然我没有用言语欺骗你，但我用不属于我的面孔欺骗了你。
to me.
不属于我。
I never meant to ruin the friendship that meant the world to me.
我从没想过要毁掉对我意义重大的友谊。
You mean the world to me.
你对我意义重大。
And now I come to you asking for forgiveness.
现在我来到你面前请求原谅。
If in your heart you find you can't, then I will understand and learn from this experience.
如果你心里觉得无法原谅，那么我会理解，并从这次经历中学习。
You came into my life at a time when I needed you the most.
你在我最需要你的时候走进了我的生活。
We talked about so many things that I started to realize my heart and my soul could actually
我们聊了那么多事情，我开始意识到我的心和灵魂其实能感受到除了伤害之外的东西。
feel something other than hurt.
除了伤害之外的东西。
You placed comfort where there was fear, confidence when there was doubt, a shoulder where tears
你在恐惧的地方带来了安慰，在怀疑的地方带来了自信，在泪水可以落下的地方带来了肩膀。
could fall and completeness where there was emptiness.
在空虚的地方带来了完整。
I wanted to hold on to this so badly that I did whatever it took for you to notice.
我太想抓住这一切了，以至于我做了任何事来引起你的注意。
What I didn't realize was that I could lose my entire being, all of who I was and all
我没有意识到的是，我可能会失去整个自我，我所有的一切和我放在你身上的一切。
of that I had placed in you.
我放在你身上的一切。
I wanted to be the one who would be there when you needed to talk.
我想成为那个在你需要倾诉时陪在你身边的人。
I wanted to be the comfort for your soul when the world was too much to handle.
我想成为你灵魂的安慰，当世界难以承受时。
I wanted to be strong for you when everything else seemed impossible.
我想在你面前坚强，当一切似乎不可能时。
I wanted to love you in only the way you deserve to be loved, never realizing that I was destroying
我想以你应得的方式爱你，却从未意识到我在摧毁自己和摧毁你。
myself and you.
摧毁自己和摧毁你。
Somehow I needed you to be a part of my life.
不知怎的，我需要你成为我生活的一部分。
The only problem was that I was willing to jeopardize everything to get that done.
唯一的问题是，我愿意不惜一切代价来实现这一点。
All the things that I told you about how I felt and how you make me feel were true.
我告诉你的关于我的感受以及你给我的感受的一切都是真的。
Nothing else mattered to me except hearing the laughter in your voice when you were happy.
除了听到你快乐时笑声中的喜悦，其他什么都不重要。
You made my days easy to get through and my nights peaceful.
你让我的日子容易度过，让我的夜晚平静。
You helped me look forward to another day.
你帮助我期待新的一天。
Even though distance separated us, just being was enough.
即使距离把我们分开，仅仅存在就足够了。
I'm sorry for hurting you and if I had to do it all over again, I would have been 100%
我很抱歉伤害了你，如果我能重来一次，我会百分之百地和你在一起。
with you.
和你在一起。
Forgive me please.
请原谅我。
Alright so what do you think he did that he's apologizing in this way?
好吧，你觉得他做了什么，让他这样道歉？
Because I don't think there were a couple right?
因为我觉得他们不是情侣，对吧？
Because he mentions friendship a couple of times.
因为他几次提到友谊。
Yes with a but.
是的，但有转折。
You don't write a letter like this to someone who you want to stay friends with.
你不会给一个你想保持朋友关系的人写这样的信。
You write a letter to this to someone who you have some kind of romantic or intense
你会给一个你对之有浪漫或强烈感情的人写这样的信，对吧？
feeling for right?
对吧？
So to me this seems like a letter that was written to someone who was a great friend
所以对我来说，这封信似乎是写给一个很好的朋友，他害怕失去她，因为他更在乎她。
and he's afraid of losing that because he cares even more for her.
他更在乎她。
Right.
对。
But yeah I guess but do you think he's confessing his love in a certain way here?
但我想，你觉得他是在以某种方式表白爱意吗？
I think in some ways he's confessing a love.
我觉得在某种程度上他是在表白爱意。
You can love your friends that's okay.
你可以爱你的朋友，这没问题。
But more than that he's just he's apologizing for something that he thinks has completely
但更重要的是，他只是在为他认为完全毁了他们友谊的事情道歉。
destroyed their friendship.
完全毁了他们友谊的事情。
And that is where I'm very confused because I have no idea what he did.
这就是我非常困惑的地方，因为我完全不知道他做了什么。
Well maybe he did something that let her down.
嗯，也许他做了让她失望的事。
Maybe he became jealous of her new boyfriend or something like that.
也许他嫉妒她的新男友之类的。
Yeah or maybe it's something catty like he was supposed to do something with her and
是啊，或者可能是些小气的事，比如他本应该和她一起做某事，结果却和别人一起做了，把她排除在外，或者当众让她难堪。
ended up doing something with other people and left her out or embarrassed her in front
当众让她难堪。
of people.
很难说。
It's hard to say.
Now have you ever written an apology letter?
你写过道歉信吗？
Yeah I have.
是的，我写过。
I've written a few apology letters.
我写过几封道歉信。
I have a very strong sense of guilt.
我有很强的负罪感。
I was raised Catholic.
我是天主教徒长大的。
So an apology letter.
所以一封道歉信。
Is it do you usually plan out what you want to say or you just like you just splurge your
你通常会计划好要说什么，还是只是把感情倾泻到纸上？
feelings onto the paper?
把感情倾泻到纸上？
Well you know me.
嗯，你了解我。
My personality is very planned and organized and so normally I have points.
我的性格非常有计划和条理，所以通常我会列出要点。
So I say if this is the problem there's three parts.
所以我会说，如果这是问题，那有三个部分。
I have an answer for each part and the very end I have the heartfelt apology.
每个部分我都有答案，最后是发自内心的道歉。
Wow.
哇。
It's like an essay.
就像写论文一样。
I guess it's a little bit more organized.
我想是更有条理一些。
If I were to write something like this I would just like start writing and whatever comes
如果我要写这样的东西，我会直接开始写，想到什么就写什么。
out.
出来。
That would probably make less sense than your letter.
那可能比你的信还要没条理。
Well I just try to stay on focus, stay on point and address the matter at hand because
嗯，我只是尽量保持专注，紧扣主题，处理眼前的问题，因为
otherwise then you get into other stuff and you can make people more angry.
否则你就会扯到别的事情，让人更生气。
Right.
对。
But it is really important to write an apology letter.
但写一封道歉信真的很重要。
Now some of the words and phrases and the vocabulary used here can be used in circumstances
现在，这里用到的一些单词、短语和词汇，也可以用在
that are not only romantic.
不仅仅是浪漫的场合。
You can use it in a professional way as well.
你也可以在职业场合使用它们。
That's true.
没错。
In a professional sense you want to be careful not to get too personal.
在职业意义上，你要小心不要搞得太私人化。
So in a professional sense it's good to say that you're sorry for any mix ups or for misunderstandings
所以在职业场合，说你对任何混乱或误解感到抱歉是好的，
but in the future you will try to make things better or improve.
但未来你会努力把事情做得更好或改进。
But in friendships and in families and in romantic relationships apology letters are
但在友谊、家庭和恋爱关系中，道歉信
very very important because I'm a big believer in mending bridges.
非常重要，因为我坚信要修复关系。
I know a lot of people who we say in English to burn a bridge that means to destroy a relationship
我知道很多人，用英语说“烧桥”，意思是破坏一段关系
and never go back.
并且再也不回头。
But I like to mend bridges to make sure that people who I was friends with don't, you know
但我喜欢“修桥”，确保我交过的朋友不会，你知道，
if we have a fight don't just hate me forever.
如果我们吵架了，就永远恨我。
That even if there's a disagreement that they understand my perspective or that I understand
即使有分歧，他们也能理解我的观点，或者我理解
theirs.
他们的观点。
That's true.
没错。
I think that's important.
我觉得那很重要。
What about apology emails?
那道歉邮件呢？
Do you agree with those?
你同意用道歉邮件吗？
I think that they are a necessity of the 21st century.
我认为它们是21世纪的必需品。
I mean I live far away from most of my friends and family and so it's important for me to
我的意思是，我住得离大多数朋友和家人很远，所以对我来说，
be able to communicate in any way.
能够以任何方式沟通很重要。
But and sometimes I mean I'm very shy with some people so sometimes it's hard for me
但有时候，我对某些人很害羞，所以有时很难
to talk on the phone because I get stuck and then I don't I can't think of what I wanted
在电话里说话，因为我会卡住，然后想不起我要
to say.
说什么。
And so if a letter helps in that way to get you past your fear or your anxiety then by
所以如果一封信能帮你克服恐惧或焦虑，那么
all means an email is just as much.
当然，电子邮件也一样有效。
I actually received a letter, a handwritten letter through an email.
我实际上收到过一封信，一封手写信，是通过电子邮件发来的。
How did that happen?
那是怎么做到的？
So the person, they scanned it, they scanned the letter.
那个人，他们扫描了它，他们扫描了那封信。
Oh wow.
哦，哇。
So it was still like it still had a very intimate and personal sense.
所以它仍然有一种非常亲密和个人的感觉。
But obviously since the mail takes so long and everything they just scanned it and then
但显然，因为邮寄太慢了，他们就直接扫描了，然后
they sent it to my email.
发到了我的邮箱。
That's nice.
那挺好的。
So I think that's a good idea.
所以我觉得这是个好主意。
Maybe you could try that one.
也许你可以试试那个方法。
I'll try that one.
我会试试那个方法。
I don't agree with the one line email.
我不同意那种只有一句话的邮件。
I'm sorry, forgive me.
“对不起，原谅我。”
Yeah, yeah, that's not good.
是啊，是啊，那不好。
As my parents always used to say when I was growing up and I'd get in fights with my little
就像我小时候，我父母常说的，当我跟我的小
brother, the only apologies that we accept are the ones that are from the heart.
弟弟吵架时，我们只接受发自内心的道歉。
So I used to have to apologize again and again and again until I actually meant it.
所以我过去不得不一遍又一遍地道歉，直到我真的发自内心。
And so I think that this is a very true kind of idea that, well maybe not in business and
所以我觉得这个想法很真实，嗯，也许在生意和
work where you have to be cordial, but with friends and real relationships with people
工作中不适用，那里你需要保持礼貌，但和朋友以及你真正在乎的人
who you care about, obviously real apologies are very important.
建立真实关系时，显然真诚的道歉非常重要。
Of course.
当然。
So this is an interesting topic and we recommend that if you have any other questions or doubts
所以这是个有趣的话题，我们建议如果你有任何其他问题或疑问，
or maybe you want some other explanation for this letter, you can come to EnglishPod.com,
或者你可能想对这封信有更多解释，你可以来EnglishPod.com，
leave it in the comment section and we'll be there.
在评论区留言，我们会在那里。
So until next time.
那么下次再见。
Bye.
拜拜。